[Music]
hi i'm nick
welcome back to 5 shake this is a nice
short video about
biscoff called speculoos in the u.s
don't know why the name is different but
over here and i think other parts of
europe
bischoff the name is a combination of
biscuits and coffee
the flavor is a caramelized cinnamon
flavor they're so popular now the last
couple of years have got a massive
resurgence i mean they've been around
for donkey's years
always used to get them in hotels on on
your pillow when you'd stay in a little
single little biscuit wrapped up but uh
so we're going to do a nice biscoff
cookies and cream
we're going to use some of this spread
here
and we're also going to use some of
these
now you can't get these everywhere
i don't know why but they are a
biscoff cookie round with a biscuit
cream in the middle
so let's just get stuck in and make it
so to make this ice cream put your milk
and sugar in a pan
and heat it up slowly to dissolve the
sugar once that's dissolved
add in 200 grams of your biscoff spread
and whisk it until it's fully
incorporated normally i'd add the cream
at this stage
but for this one we're going to leave
that out once it's all ready
put it into a container in your fridge
what i did here is add the cream at this
stage and it drops the temperature of
your base down really quickly it means
you only have to keep it in the fridge
for an hour or two
once a base is chilled put it in your
ice cream machine and churn as you would
do normally
in my machine this will take about 10 to
12 minutes but in others it might take
half an hour
once your ice cream's churning take your
biscoff cookies
and chop them up nice and small you
don't want them all really small you
want some big chunks in there as well
put them in a tub ready for when your
ice cream is churned
when your ice cream is ready we're going
to load the tub up now just don't scrimp
on the cookies like everyone else does
put loads in there so you get a really
good taste of it the ice cream
flavor is really heavy of biscoff so you
might as well get a whole hog
and put loads of biscoff cookies in
there as well pop it in the freezer when
it's ready
and we'll take it out in a few hours
[Music]
got the top out of the freezer let's get
some in a bowl and see what it looks
[Music]
like
look at it it looks incredible i'll put
a picture of the top here but
obviously you you can see loads of bits
of the cookie in there these cookies
smell
incredible so i mean if you don't know
what biscoff or speculoos
smell like or taste like then just go
and try some they're great
the actual ice cream itself
let's try it
the base is really creamy you can taste
the actual biscuits the flavor
of biscoff come through a lot it's a
very heavy flavor in that base
you get the little crunch of those
cookies in there as well and most people
you know these big store brands they
there's not a lot in there the cookies
and cream of various flavors there's not
a lot of cookies in there it's more
cream
so don't scrimp on the cookies
put loads in so you've got a crunch in
every bite but the actual cookies are an
amazing flavor in themselves
do try this it's really simple really
easy you can buy all the bits in the
shops as it is
great flavor very popular hope you enjoy
this one we're actually working on a
massive video in the background for our
150 subscriber mark which we'll hope to
get to
soon it's a big video so just you know
be prepared for that one
for now thank you very much for watching
remember to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next time